alxmrtnz.com
alex@alxmrtnz.com

Introduction

I'm Alex, a product designer and front-end developer with a passion for crafting beautiful interfaces and delightful experiences.

I have worked with both agencies and startups to create digital products for web and mobile. I have a deep passion for user-centered design and front-end code.

Skills and Technologies

UX/UI Design, Product Design, Front-End Design/Development

Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, Invision, Balsamiq, Omnigraffle, HTML, Sass, Gulp/Preprocessors, Javascript, Jekyll.

Education

Ohio University 2010-2014

Graduated Magna Cum Laude with a Bachelor of Science in Visual Communication and a minor in Computer Science in spring 2014. King-Chavez-Parks Scholarship Award recipient and Dean's List student.

Experience

iStrategyLabs MAY 2014 - PRESENT

Web and product designer for ISL, a Washington, D.C.–based digital agency. I have worked with clients like the Family Online Safety Institute, Washington Leadership Academy, Sheetz and NCOC. I have also served as designer and front-end developer on internal projects.

Through ISL, I work as one of two UI/UX designers on Service Year, a platform that connects American youth with year-long service opportunities through national non-profit organizations. I have been working remotely for ISL from Toledo, OH since May 2016.

Metto AUGUST 2013 - PRESENT

Partner and founder of Metto, a (fully-remote) product design and development studio that creates business critical web applications. I serve as creative director and UI/UX designer.

I frequently work within our team's development environment (Python, Django, Gulp) to implement front-end and interactive designs.

Jersey Watch AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2014

Product designer and front-end developer for Jersey Watch, an Ohiobased startup that provides websites to youth sports organizations.

I worked on a redesign of their client-facing product and partnered with their team's lead developer to implement front-end updates to the company's public-facing marketing site.

Viget JUNE 2013 - AUGUST 2013

UX design intern at Viget Lab's Boulder, CO office. I shadowed the UX team on client projects and contributed to work including:

- User experience for an intern team project, an online game of Rock Paper Scissors
- An internal presentation on the use of hand gestures as input devices
- Various client projects